So, many times you people have questions about personal accidental insurance that
we have taken a health insurance policy.
Personal accidental needs to be taken separately
and is personal accidental
not covered in our health insurance policy?  So the
answer to this is that personal accidental
insurance is
taken over and above your health insurance policy.
Accidental hospitalization
is covered under your health insurance.  Suppose there is
any hospitalization due to an accident, then it
is covered in your health insurance policy.  But there are many such benefits
which are disability benefits and are
covered in your personal accidental policy.  That is
why it is
important to take a separate personal accidental policy.
And the second thing that your health insurance is is an
indemnity policy.  This means that the insurance company will pay the claim based on the
loss you have suffered and the claim received.
Where a
personal accidental policy is a fixed
benefit policy.  Because you have suffered a loss, an
accident, a death, or a disability, the
compensation due to that is
paid out as a lump sum benefit to you or
your beneficiary nominee.  So, based on this,
you people have asked which personal
accidental insurance policy should be taken?
So today we are comparing four policies
which are personal accidental insurance
policies, we will compare them
in detail.  This is a comprehensive analysis.   Stay tuned
till the end of the video.  If you are
looking to take a personal accidental policy.
So this is your go to video for the same.
Before starting the video, I would like to
introduce myself.  My name
is Gurleen Kotik and I am a Certified
Financial Planner.  I have been
associated with the insurance industry for the last 20 years
and every week I bring videos for you
so that your insurance bank
journey becomes easy and happy.  Because the
tagline of our company is also
Creating a Wealth of Happening.  Let's move on to the
video where we will talk about the top four
personal accidental insurance policies.  So before that
I would like to talk about the
accident.  So what is an accident basically
?  So what is the definition of accident
?  When we look at it from the insurance point of view,
accident is basically an
incident.  So if we
define it, it means a
sudden unforced or involuntary act which
happened due to external factors.  It
is visible.  It appears that there was injury and violence.
So this is considered in the definition of accident.  The
accident happened while walking on the road.
Which is the most common form of
accident.  You slipped down the stairs.
That is also called the accident.  So if
it leads to injury then it is counted as an
accident.  And you get that accidental injury
claim in personal accidental policies.
So in what form can the claim be made
?  Either there will be accidental death or
disability or there will be something due to which there is
temporary disability.  For example,
in case of fractures or broken bones, your personal accidental
insurance policy compensates you.
Now suppose in this same example the bone was broken
and the doctor said that surgery would be required.
So it is covered in your health insurance policy.
But in the earlier example,
if it is OPD treatment
then no health insurance policy will cover it.
And the best part is
that its cost is not linked to age.  It is not linked to your age.
Like in health insurance, if
your age is higher then the premium will be
higher.  The cost of accident policies
remains the same through every age.
Because the chances of accident, the
probability is similar.  At young age as well as at
higher age.  And the
cost of these personal accidental insurance policies is
very low.  Meaning where you pay a
hefty premium for health insurance.
Here
you get a big cover at a very low premium.   We will
talk in detail about four personal
accidental insurance pluses.
Which ones are they?  Neevapa Personal Accidental
Plan HDFC Arbo Co Poti Suraksha Aditya
Birla Active Secure Tata AIG Personal
Accident Guard Plus Plan So we will
talk about these four plans,
what is the coverage in these plans, what is not covered,
what is the eligibility criteria, who
can take this policy and lastly we will talk about the
premiums, so stay till the end of the video,
so if we talk about the entry age,
who can enter in these policies, so
in Neeva Personal Accidental Plan the minimum
entry age is 18 years, maximum there
is no limit, dependent children from 91 days to 25
years can be
covered in the parents' policy as a family floater.  The
minimum entry age for HDFC Arbo Koti Suraksha is 18 and the maximum is 65.
Aditya Birla Active Secure Plan minimum
entry age is 5 years and maximum is 65
years.  The minimum entry age for Tata AIG Personal Accidental
Guard Plus plan is 18.
The maximum is 70 years.  Dependent
children can be added till 23 years.
Ads can last from six months to 23 years.  Now let's
talk about the eligibility criteria.
Under the Neema Bupa Personal Accidental Plan,
if you are a salaried person, you can get
cover up to 20 times your annual income.  Suppose
your income is Rs 10 lakh, then the eligibility is up to Rs 2 crore.
So if this cover is increased 25 times
then you can get a cover of Rs 2.5 crore.
Unearned income: Suppose you have
rental income, you have pension income.
In that case, you can take cover up to a maximum of 15 times
your income.  If it is non-earning then
maximum cover of Rs 50 lakh will be given.
Times of Annual Income for Earning Persons in HDFC Ergo Koti Suraksha Plan.
If you are earning then only 10 times of annual
income will be given to you.  In Aditya Birla
Active Secure Plan, if you are earning then
you are eligible for cover up to 12 times of annual income.
And if
you also opt for Loan Protect Rider,
you can avail maximum cover of 15 times your income.  Sum Ash of TTD Next we will
understand what is TTD?  There is a Temporary Total
Disability Benefit.  We will understand this in detail later.
So for now the TTD sum
assured is
two times of annual gross income for salaried and self employed.
TTD Sub Sum Assured can be up to two times your income.  If the person is non-
earning, then only 100% of the basic cover or ₹30
lakh maximum will be given.  And if you have
children, in case of children only 100% of
basic cover or maximum Rs 15 lakh will be given.
Which ever is lower.  Let's talk about plan options.
What plans
or variants are available?
Variant One to Variant Six
are available in Neevapa.  You can choose
what benefits you want.  Next we will
talk about the benefits.  There are some benefits
which are available in all the plans.  There are some benefits
which are available only in the higher variants.
You can choose the variant as per your choice if
you want those benefits.  There are
four plans available in Air Koti Suraksha.  10
lakhs, 25 lakhs, 50 lakhs and 1 crore.
You can choose any of these four.
Accordingly, the amount of your benefits will be
decided.
Five options 1 2 3 4 5 are available in Aditya Birla Active Secure Plan.
You can choose which one
you want.  And lastly, Tata AIG
Personal Accident Guard Plus is available in
three options: Protect, Elite and Premier.
Next we will understand what these
options are.  Now let's talk about sum assured.
How much sum assured can you take?
Niva Personal Accidental Plan has a minimum cover of Rs
5 lakh.
You can also take cover up to a maximum of Rs 10 crore.  The minimum security cover in HDFC Ago Kot
is 10 lakhs.  Maximum
cover available up to Rs 1 crore.  The
minimum deposit in Aditya Birla Active Secure is ₹1 lakh.
Maximum cover available is ₹20 crore.  So the
window is very large.  So then I said Plan 1
2 3 4 5, all the options are available there.
Tata AIG Personal Accident Guard
Plus has a minimum cover of Rs 5 lakh and a maximum cover of Rs 5 crore.
So again subject to financial
eligibility.  As we discussed that you
should be financially eligible and
how much sum assured you can take.  Just like it happens
in term insurance, the same happens
in your personal accidental insurance.
Insurance companies do not check age eligibility in health insurance.
Financial Eligibility: You
can take as much cover as you want.  But
in personal accidental, you will have to take cover as per your income.
If you have already taken a personal
accidental policy, then when you are going to
take a new personal accidental policy, you will
tell them like your term
insurance policy.  So the total cover that you have is this many
times.  If it is 10 times then
total 10 times.  For example, if your
income is 10 lakhs and your eligibility is
10 times.  For example, you
can take insurance only up to 10 times.  This means
you can have a personal accidental cover of Rs 1 crore.
Total of all the companies combined.  You have to
make sure that when you take a new policy or
enhance your cover, you do
not forget to mention the old cover.
One year, two year, three year
policies are available in all policy tenures.  If you pay premium for two or three years
together, you
get discounts.  Multi Tenure
Discount Discount.  Emergency Accidental
Hospitalization because an accident can
also lead to hospitalization.  So
accidental hospitalization is also covered in these policies.
Niwamba has you covered with 10%
off all assured.  You can avail cover up to a maximum of Rs 5 lakh
in case of accidental
hospitalization.  So, if there is any hospitalization due to an accident, it is
not necessary that you use your health insurance
policy.  You
can also use your personal accidental policy.
What will happen with this?  If you have any no claim
bonuses or lock the clock benefits, then
they will not be affected.  So you can claim from here also.
Benefit up to Rs 1 lakh is available in HDFC RO quota protection.
Aditya Birla Active Secure Plan has
optional cover.  You will have to get it added by paying additional premium.
Is 1%.
Accidental hospitalization cover up to a maximum of Rs 1 lakh
is available.  Tata AIG Personal Accident
Guard Plus offers 10% of sum assured.
Maximum cover available is up to Rs 5 lakh.
Emergency road ambulance is also covered.   The
Neevapa Personal Accidental Van costs ₹25,000.
HDFCO has everything within ₹1 lakh.
Hospitalization and Ambulance
is ₹1,000 in Aditya Birla Active Secure.  Up
to ₹10,000 and
up to ₹25,000 is available in Tata AIG Personal Accidental Guard Plus.
Bonus is also available on
accidental death sum assured which we talked about, be it
1 lakh or 5 lakh, as per percentage of your sum
assured, no
claim bonus is given on that, there is
5% no claim bonus in Nivapa, it
is not there in HDFC, there is 5% in your Aitya Bla AI sky also,
maximum 50% and 10% in Tata AIG,
maximum up to 50%, now let's talk about
coverage, so first of all what will be actually covered in your
policies, because when you are
taking the policy, there is an accident, so there are
chances of death due to accident also.  So
accidental death
is covered in all four of your policies and up to sum assured means
100% of sum assured.  If the policy is of Rs 1 crore
then Rs 1 crore will be given and if the
accidental death is of Rs 2 crore then Rs 2 crore will be given and if the policy is of Rs 10
crore then Rs 10 crore will be given.  Of course,
investigation is done because it is a big
amount, so the insurance company
pays the claim only after complete verification.
So they have to be sure that it was an
accident.  That whole definition is
qualifying.  The
financial eligibility that you had taken at whatever income level, is
it being fulfilled or
not, only after it is fully verified, the
end subject document
because if there has been an accidental death, then FIR
and MLC are two important documents
which you have to provide.
FIR is First Information Report MLC
Medical Legal Certificate.  This is generally
provided in cases of accidental death.
Next comes
permanent total disability.  Now an accident
happened, there was no death, there was permanent total
disability.  So what will happen in that case
?  Percentage of sum assured.  Now it depends on
what loss has occurred.  If there is loss of limes then
percentage will be given accordingly.  If there is loss
of vision then it is accordingly.  If there is loss of one
hand then it is accordingly.  If there is loss of one
finger then the percentage is defined accordingly
which will be given to you in these policies.   Then
comes permanent, partial disability.   There is
some disability which has become permanent
but is partial, not complete.  Meaning,
in partial we can say that the hand was not
damaged.  If one finger is cut, it is permanent or
partial.  The percentage is defined in that too.
You have tables given in your policies.  The
lump sum benefit will be paid out accordingly.  There are
two types of TT available in Personal Accidental Plan.  TTD
Plus & TT Lite. So the premium for both
is different.  This is an optional rider.  Accordingly, you
can choose TTD Plus or TTD Lite.
TTD plus 2% of sum assured maximum
₹75,000 and for 52 weeks.  And if you take TTD Lite then
1% of sum assured maximum
₹50,000 for 100 weeks.  HDFCO quota
security has 1% off sub assured.
Maximum ₹1 lakh will be given to you for 104
weeks.
This rider is optional in Aditya Birla Active Secure Plan.  Weekly benefit is
1000, 2000 3000 4 5 7500 10000 and up to
₹0000.  The maximum TTD you will receive can be
only two times your income.  You will
not get more than that and
you can take it for a maximum of 100 weeks.
Then let's talk about Tata Ag Personal
Accidental Guard Plus, TTD benefit
is also optional.  Protect is optional,
meaning you will have to add it by paying additional premium
and it is
inbuilt in Elite and Premier plans.  You can avail this benefit up to 1% of Accidental Death Sum
Assured and Rs 50,000 for a maximum period of 104 weeks.
Now let's talk about
loan protector or EMI
protector.  Many times it happens that if there is a death,
who will repay the loan?  So there
is also the Loan Protector add on.  You
can also get an EMI protector.  So like
in MIV bua you can take your loan protector add on.
It is optional.  Here if loan
protector add on is taken.  The
outstanding principal amount at the
date of death up to the maximum sum assured will be
given to the beneficiary.  This benefit
is not available.  HDFC Ergo Koti Suraksha.
Aditya Bill is a loan protector at Active Secure.  There
is an option from Rs 1 lakh to Rs 1 crore.  You can choose three EMIs up to Rs 50,000 and Rs
75,000.
Premium will be charged accordingly.  You can get EMI waiver up to ₹5 lakh
by
choosing this.  Tata AIG plan covers up to
25% of sum assured and actuals
whichever is less.  So, whatever your sum
assured is, if you die, then 25% of the
loan amount will be given to the beneficiary or the
actual loan amount will be given
whichever is lesser.  Adventure
Sports is an optional rider up to
100% of Permanent Total Disability Sum
Assured in Nivafa and is not available in HDFCO.
In Aadat Birla Active Secure, this
accidental death cover
is available up to the sum assured equal to Rs 10 lakh or maximum Rs 10 lakh.
This is not available in Tata LEG plan.
In Compassionate Visit, 2% of base sum
assured up to a maximum of Rs 50,000 will be given
in case of Compassionate Visit.  This
is not available in HDFCO.  In Aditya Birla AI Secure,
if there is a domestic visit, meaning you have met with an
accident and your family members are
reaching you, then on compassionate
grounds, ₹10,000 will be given to them for domestic visit
and ₹25,000 for international visit,
which is a fixed benefit.  So no such
option is available in Tata IC
plan.  Then transportation of fecal
remains.  If death occurs and repression is to be done, the
remains of the body are removed from one
part to another.  If it has to be brought to your home, the
insurance company also covers the tow transportation cost.
So in Neevapa, up
to 1% of sum assured up to maximum ₹1 lakh will be
given for transportation cost.
Transportation cost option is not available in HDFC ao.
Aditya Birla Active Secure
also offers a lump sum benefit of
₹50,000.  Tata AIG plan offers up to 1%
of sum assured up to a maximum of ₹25,000.
Now let us come to funeral expenses or
also called last rights expenses.  That
too is covered in your Niva Book plan.
Up to 1% of sum assured up to a
maximum of ₹1 lakh.  ₹10,000 in HDFCO Kotak Suraksha
1% of sum assured maximum ₹50,000 in Aitya Birla Active Secure.  Tata
EIG Personal Accident Guard Plus
combines this with transportation of motor
remains.  So the total amount will be Rs 25,000
including funeral and transportation of
mortal remains by air ambulance.  Now covered up to
20% of Accidental Death Sum Assured.
Maximum 5 will be given.  And
not available in HDFC Ergo.
Not available in Aditya Birla Active Secure also.
Tata AIG Personal Accident Guard Plus
offers cover up to Rs 5 lakh.
Hospital Daily Cash NIVPA @ 25% of Base
Sum Assured per day maximum Rs. 5000 for 30 days.
So, whatever is your sum assured, maximum
5% of it and maximum ₹5000 will be given per day
and it will be given for maximum 30 days only.
HDFCO quota security will be given at ₹3000 per
day for a maximum of 30 days.
This is not available in Aditya Birla Active Secure.
In Tata AIG, 5% of
Accidental Death Sum Assured and Rs 5000 whichever is less will be
given for maximum 60 days.
Accidental OPD is available at Neema Buba in
which you will be given up to 1% of base
sum assured maximum Rs 25,000.
HDFC Arbo KT security not available.   It is
not available in Aditya Birla and
also not available in Tata Ag.  So as
I said, different variants
are available.  So Accidental OPD is available in higher variants.
Not available in lower variants.  So you
can check according to your need what you
need.  Finalize the variant or
plan accordingly.  Monthly Any Benefit
where a monthly amount will be given to the
family.  Which is 5% of base sum assured
per month.  Maximum ₹50,000 per month is given
for 3 months.  This
option is available only in Neevapa.  The rest don't have it.
Elderly Care: If there are elders or parents in the house, then
10% of the
base sum assured up to a maximum of ₹ lakh will be given in the Nivapa for their care.
HDFC Arbo Koti Suraksha will
offer 5% of base sum assured up to a maximum of ₹1 lakh.  Benefit is not available in Aditya Birla and Tata Ag.
Education of
Dependent Children: If there are dependent
children, the company will also bear the cost of their education.
So in Nevapa, you will pay an expense of 10% of base
sum assured up to a maximum of ₹5 lakh.
In HDFC categories, you will pay 10% of sum
assured up to a maximum of ₹1 lakh.
Aditya Bla Active Secure offers 10% of base
sum assured up to a maximum of ₹1 lakh.  In Tata AIG,
if the child is below 23 years of age, a
fixed sum will be given.  Which is 10% of sum
assured or ₹1 lakh whichever is less.
Broken bones.  Now suppose a bone is broken, even then
fixed benefit will be given.
Percentage will be given in Neema Bupa policy.  Will
give maximum up to ₹1 lakh.  In case
of broken bones, your bonus is
up to ₹1 lakh in HDFC Ergo Koti Suraksha,
up to ₹1 lakh in Aditya Birla Active Secure, up to ₹3 lakh, ₹5
lakh in S. According to which bone is broken, a maximum
cover of up to ₹5 lakh is available.
Next is modifications made at home and
vehicle. Many times, due to accidents, a
ramp has to be made in the house, a railing has to be made,
holding which you will walk, then that
modification may have to be done in the house.
After accident, 25% of base sum
assured maximum ₹5 lakh will be given in HDFC Ergo. This is
not covered in HDFC Ergo.
Up to 1 lakh in Aitya Bla Activ Scur and not covered in Tata AIG.
Prosthetics or Wheelchair: You have to
buy a wheelchair because of an
accident or you have to get an artificial leg.
I am giving you an example of
prosthetics.  It looks like an artificial limb
, it looks like an artificial leg.
Even in that case the insurance company is
giving you compensation.  So Neema is giving you compensation up to
₹1 lakh.
This option is not available in HDFC Agar Koti Suraksha.
Not available in Aditya Birla Active Secure also.  In Tata IG Personal Guard
Accident Plus Plan, you will
get the cost of wheelchair up to 10% of accidental death sum
or maximum ₹1 lakh and also the cost of prosthetics,
which we said is artificial limbs, up
to ₹1 lakh will be given.   Even
if someone goes into coma
due to an accident, the insurance
company still pays a fixed benefit.  Nima
Bupa has 25% off base sum assured.   Will be done
on maximum ₹1 lakh.  HDFC
Ergo Koti Suraksha will provide compensation of 50% of base sum
assured subject to a maximum of ₹2 lakh.
In Aditya Birla Active Secure, benefit equal to accidental death sum
assured maximum will be given.  ₹1 Lakh
in Tata AIG 10% off sum assured up to maximum ₹5
Lakh will be given for Komaz.  See you Burn
Scheme.  If you get burns in an accident,
what will you get?  In Neevapa, you will
get amount up to best sum assured
maximum ₹50 lakh.  HDFCO offers
up to Rs 75,000 in Quote Security and this benefit is not available in Aditya Birla and Tata H.
Head and
Spinal Injury
A fixed benefit
is available in the Nima BPA policy if there is a head and spine injury.  Which is 2% of
base sum assured maximum ₹1 lakh.
Not available in other policies.  Accident
Care.  So, due to accidents, many times there will be
such things which you need to take care of at home.
So in that the
benefit is available only in Neema Bhupa.  Not in other plans.
Which is called ICU at home.
So this percentage will be given to you.
Different amounts are mentioned.
You can see it on your screen.  Some
discounts are available.
Your multi tenure discount is available at Neema Bhupa.
Now if you pay the premium for two or three years together, then
multi tenure discount
is available.  And HDFCO quota security also has
multi tenure.
Multi-tenure discount
is available in Aditya Birla Active Secure.  And
multi-tenure discount is also available in Tata AIG Personal Guard Accident Plus plan.
So here are the details
about four personal accidental plans for
which maximum details were available.
We have tried to cover it by doing research.  If
you have any questions, please
ask in the comment section.  You
can reach out to us.  Now finally we will talk
about their premiums.  Premiums are
on your screen.  So the criteria for taking sum assured will
depend on your income.  The
amount of sum assured you can take will be decided according to your income.  You will
get TT benefit when you are earning.
So it is important for you to take care of all these things.
And here also the proposal form
is important.  Because here you are
writing your income.  You are writing your occupation.
Many times there are occupations in
which personal accidental insurance will not be
available.  So there are different risk categories of
insurance companies.  For example, if you
work on a ship, you will
not get personal accidental insurance.   If you
work in the mining industry, or
in mines in coal fields, you will
not get it.  If the risk is high then the
insurance company will not provide it.  If you are
in the army, you will not get personal accidental insurance.
So there are many things
which are not available.  So mention your occupation
properly, do not mention it wrongly because your
claim may be denied in future.  If you
are salaried then mention your salary only.  If you
are self-employed then mention self-employed only.
State your actual income and submit your ITR,
Statement of Income, Salary Slips or
Form 16 to the insurance company in
advance.  So that there is no disappointment at the time of claim.
And if you have
not yet taken a personal accidental insurance policy,
then it is time to buy one because it
financially secures your family.
Many times I have seen that there
is a health insurance policy but there is
no personal accidental policy due to which the
family faces challenges.
What should you do if there is a loss of income?  You get fixed
benefit which is TTD weekly benefit which
actually helps.  So,
you must consider taking this policy.  If you have
any questions, reach out in the comment section.  If
you want to reach out to our team, the
contact number link is mentioned below.  You
can fill it in.  Our team will
contact you and you can also email us.
If you found the video useful,
please share it with your friends and
family who are struggling.   Should one
take a personal accidental policy or not
and if one should take it then which one should one take.
And before we go, a quick reminder,
if you haven't subscribed to our channel yet, please do so.
So that you get
the right infection at the right time.  See you
in the next video with a new topic.  Till then
stay safe.  Take care.  Bye bye.